<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-17T17:14:43+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mohsen Ahmadi, Agile PM</title><subtitle>Agile Product/Project Manager and Scrum Master,  with the successful product/project management history.  Highly skilled in collaborating with team members to achieve business and financial goals.  Also, Python Lover, Coffee Addict, Have a Big Dream, Nutella, Workout, Travel and Backpacker.</subtitle><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><entry><title type="html">Attention! Niko-Niko Calendar, it’s important to any Agile teams</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/attention-niko-niko-calendar-its-important-to-any-agile-teams" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attention! Niko-Niko Calendar, it’s important to any Agile teams" /><published>2018-08-11T00:00:00+04:30</published><updated>2018-08-11T00:00:00+04:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/attention-niko-niko-calendar-its-important-to-any-agile-teams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/attention-niko-niko-calendar-its-important-to-any-agile-teams">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imgpsts/niko-niko-jira.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Niko-Niko Calendar, it’s important to any Agile teams&quot; /&gt;
One of the terms or concepts in #Agile is the Information Radiator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This terms actually refers to a series of information markers about the project and your products that displays activities of the development’s team to all key-stockholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of using this charts is the team does not hide anything throughout the project, increase the responsibility of team members and it can help the rest of the project’s status by stockholders without asking by team members. (They can look for the large boards and somehow exposed to them.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of these indicators referred to 1980s and the &lt;strong&gt;KANBAN&lt;/strong&gt; leaders in &lt;strong&gt;TOYOTA&lt;/strong&gt; and trying to improve their processes by technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The burn-down chart, storyboard, planning board and etc are some of the samples of these indicators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imgpsts/Niko-Niko.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Niko-Niko Calendar&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this text, I try to write about the Niko-Niko calendar that’s introduced by &lt;em&gt;Akinori Sakata&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simple board is a matter of day-to-day experience of them’s members. As each day and after the daily standup meeting show by stickers happy or sad to show how they are going today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main benefits of this board for team‘ members and PM is that during each sprint the status of the team is identified for the rest of the team and the project manager, scrum master and even the members of the team will appreciate more and more mutual understanding and help to make a better connection. And also, if any of the members are not happy, the rest of the people will give them the energy that will bring their happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niko-Niko Calendar is a best practical exercise to discover the mood of your Agile team members and helps to solve a lot of problem before the explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you save the information that’s recorded on this board, you can re-examine the intervals, for example, three or six months and see what the team’s mental state is about, what to do and what positive things you can do to keep the team are happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This Article is Updated on 2019-06-05&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mohsenahmadi/niko-niko-calendar-its-important-to-any-agile-team-62e4b2aa4410&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Medium Page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><category term="Agile" /><category term="Project Management" /><category term="Scrum" /><summary type="html">One of the terms or concepts in #Agile is the Information Radiator.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">As a Product or Project manager, you should do these works weekly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/as-a-product-or-project-manager-you-should-do-these-works-weekly" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="As a Product or Project manager, you should do these works weekly" /><published>2018-02-17T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-02-17T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/as-a-product-or-project-manager-you-should-do-these-works-weekly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/as-a-product-or-project-manager-you-should-do-these-works-weekly">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imgpsts/photo-1436367050586-7c605120bf73.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Product Managers Weekly Tasks&quot; /&gt;
Despite the general definition of the Project / Product management, which is temporary and unique management is not immediate and temporary. As a Project/Product Manager, you have a number of tasks to be done daily and weekly. But at the same time, you should not be involved in your daily routine and let routine works lead you to a steady pace.
One of the attractiveness of Project/Product management (for me at least) is the existence of challenges that can occur during project/product management. Challenges that make you think differently.
In this text, I’ll take a glimpse of the tasks that you have to do as a weekly project/product management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Meeting customers/stakeholders&lt;/strong&gt;
The customers/stakeholders are the keys and the main element of each project/product. As long as the client does not exist, no projects will be formed. You have the least distance between yourself and your customers. Talk to them weekly, provide them with a brief overview of the progress or reasons for the project’s backwardness and hear their concerns and discuss with them the possible future risks of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Evaluation of project/product progress&lt;/strong&gt;
Spending time with the project/product team on a weekly basis can increase your confidence in the progress of the work, and if there is a backlash in the projects, the root causes and corrective actions are the responsibility of controlling and directing them best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Review the project/product memories&lt;/strong&gt;
Check the risks files of the project on a weekly basis and review and update them. Each moment you move forward with the project, the risk and risks log of your project also change. Always update this file by moving it forward with the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Reviewing the criteria for updating&lt;/strong&gt;
Update metrics check the percentages of project’s progress with the members of the project team. If the previous criteria are incorrect, modify them and always keep the progress of your project under control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Distribution of progress reports&lt;/strong&gt;
Write the progress of the project and the achievements in one-page report and distribute it to all stakeholders and team members,
The budget and remaining information, the report of the percentage of physical progress, the time of arrival at the miles and the points of interest can form part of the title of your report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Look at the project/product from above (helicopter look)&lt;/strong&gt;
Just like riding a helicopter, look at the top of your project and product. Make a bigger picture of the project. Behind the table, you long viewing angle limits your vision and makes difficult to make decisions. By changing your viewing angle, you can significantly help improve team performance and as a result, improve your product/project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Examining effective metrics&lt;/strong&gt;
Always check the metrics that affect the progress and success of your product/project. If any of these metrics are suddenly reduced or increased, you should check the cause and identify the reasons for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><category term="Product Management" /><category term="Product Launch" /><summary type="html">Despite the general definition of the Project / Product management, which is temporary and unique management is not immediate and temporary. As a Project/Product Manager, you have a number of tasks to be done daily and weekly. But at the same time, you should not be involved in your daily routine and let routine works lead you to a steady pace. One of the attractiveness of Project/Product management (for me at least) is the existence of challenges that can occur during project/product management. Challenges that make you think differently. In this text, I’ll take a glimpse of the tasks that you have to do as a weekly project/product management.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What does do Product Managers?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/what-does-do-product-managers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What does do Product Managers?" /><published>2018-02-06T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-02-06T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/what-does-do-product-managers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/what-does-do-product-managers">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imgpsts/marketing-campaign-learning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Product Manager Job&quot; /&gt;
As you know, the #Product_Management is one of the most important roles for the successful any business in IT industry. But this concept doesn’t have much age in this industry and maybe make some conflict between the other important roles such as #Product_Owner and #Project_Manager.
In this text, I’ll try to clear some points in in this position as follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step, I’ll explain what does doing every #product_manager in IT industry.
Every product manager should help to another team and department to grow the business and arrange them like as a conductor. It’s so near the project manager’s role in this field.
On Google, you can find this definition of the product manager:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Product Manager helps their team (and company) ship the right product to their users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we would find the product manager involved which team to help them. Designers, engineers, QA, documentation, marketing and all of the stakeholders of your product in business needs to your help.
Some expert people believe the product manager must play as a CEO in organizations for growing the product. But I think leadership in this role is more important to anything. Although the authority is important too. You should be managing the product by building the useful and SMART roadmap and clear that to all the teams.
On clarifying the roadmap for other teams you can gather the votes for features with important factors such as business impact, technical effort, facilitate the operational staff and make customers happy.
After these steps and clear your roadmap, as a product manager, you must share it with all internal stakeholders and get their confirmation as soon as possible. You could set a deadline for this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget the company’s overall goals and objectively covered in your prioritizing roadmap features and also, your team capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your position is most important to track all competitors every day
and monitor all your metrics to grow your product.
Set periodic sessions with all internal stakeholders and find all teams understand the challenge, product value target for delivering to end users, and get their feedback (internal stakeholders by listening and external stakeholders by tracing them on social media activities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a product manager you must know this point:
Your job is never done and you must improvement plan, additional testing, tracing market and competitors, response to your customers and analyze your data forever. When a product is dead, your job is finish and you must go home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ahmadi.space/assets/imgpsts/PMSC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What does do Product Managers?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of this texts, you must know As a product manager, you never go to write code because it is engineering role, you don’t create mock-ups for designer and you don’t have to make a marketing or PR plans. You must lead the all team without directly involved that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><category term="Product Management" /><category term="Product Owner" /><summary type="html">As you know, the #Product_Management is one of the most important roles for the successful any business in IT industry. But this concept doesn’t have much age in this industry and maybe make some conflict between the other important roles such as #Product_Owner and #Project_Manager. In this text, I’ll try to clear some points in in this position as follow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Check these points before you launch any Products</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/check-these-points-before-you-launch-any-product" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Check these points before you launch any Products" /><published>2018-02-03T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2018-02-03T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/check-these-points-before-you-launch-any-product</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/check-these-points-before-you-launch-any-product">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ahmadi.pm/assets/imgpsts/mp900405500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Product Launch Checklist&quot; /&gt;
At the previous story, I told trying to write story series on my experience as a Product Manager in a new business field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this story, I’ll write about an important concept in a structured company that moves the encounter to obscure issues as a new PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s sudden for me. In first days I must be knowing more about GDS (Global Distribution System) concept and create a road-map for migrating all working services and made many micro-service for using other product lines. So, I should prioritize tasks by business KPIs, Technical effort and also I can’t stop current workflow in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking with domain expert’s developers and investigation by other teams (Marketing, Sales, Customer support, etc) I decided to start the first version and improve that again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the first step, I make a new mind-map and write all features, requirements and then classified them. Now, I found better look about this migration and relations between services and product lines. After this step, trying to classification these items to Theme, Epic, and Story via Google Sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these two simple steps, I accomplished better look about this migration and next steps.
In next story, I’ll write about our rules to make Epic, Story, Requirements, and Tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><category term="Product Management" /><category term="Product Launch" /><category term="Product Owner" /><summary type="html">At the previous story, I told trying to write story series on my experience as a Product Manager in a new business field.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A little light on Black-hole</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/a-little-light-on-black-hole" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A little light on Black-hole" /><published>2017-10-24T00:00:00+03:30</published><updated>2017-10-24T00:00:00+03:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/a-little-light-on-black-hole</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/a-little-light-on-black-hole">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/imgpsts/light.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little light on Black-hole&quot; /&gt;
At the previous story, I told trying to write story series on my experience as a Product Manager in a new business field.
In this story, I’ll write about an important concept in a structured company that moves the encounter to obscure issues as a new PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s sudden for me. In first days I must be knowing more about GDS (Global Distribution System) concept and create a road-map for migrating all working services and made many micro-service for using other product lines. So, I should prioritize tasks by business KPIs, Technical effort and also I can’t stop current workflow in this way.
After talking with domain expert’s developers and investigation by other teams (Marketing, Sales, Customer support, etc) I decided to start the first version and improve that again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the first step, I make a new mind-map and write all features, requirements and then classified them. Now, I found better look about this migration and relations between services and product lines. After this step, trying to classification these items to Theme, Epic, and Story via Google Sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these two simple steps, I accomplished better look about this migration and next steps.
In next story, I’ll write about our rules to make Epic, Story, Requirments, and Tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mohsen Ahmadi</name><email>mohsen@ahmadi.pm</email></author><category term="Product Management" /><category term="Product Owner" /><summary type="html">At the previous story, I told trying to write story series on my experience as a Product Manager in a new business field. In this story, I’ll write about an important concept in a structured company that moves the encounter to obscure issues as a new PM.</summary></entry></feed>